Guide to the Anne Hadden Collection, 1869-1935
Department of Special Collections
Anne Hadden Collection,
1869-1935
Special Collections M0103
Hadden, Anne.
.25 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Gift of Elizabeth, Fannie, and Georgina Evelyn Hadden, 1964.
Biography
Anne Hadden was a librarian in Palo Alto and Monterey, California.
Scope and Content
Includes letters received by Anne Hadden, Irene Hardy, and Maude J. Wilson. Also includes letters collected by Miss Hardy. Correspondents include Edward Everett Hale, Oliver Wendell Holmes, Horace Mann, John Muir, Lincoln Steffens, John Steinbeck, and Woodrow Wilson.
Access terms
Anderson, Melville Best, 1851-1933.; Barton, Clara, 1821-1912.; Carruth, William Herbert, 1859-1924.; Dana, James Dwight, 1813-1895.; Dana, Richard Henry, 1815-1882.; Darby, S. C.; Dodge, Mary Abigail, 1833-1896.; Dudley, W. R.; Elliott, Ellen Coit.; Flugel, Ewald, 1863-1914.; Hadden, Anne.; Hale, Edward Everett, 1822-1909.; Hale, Ellen Day.; Hamilton, Mary Abigail, 1833-1896.; Hardy, Ir`ene, 1841-; Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878.; Holmes, Oliver Wendell, 1809-1894.; Jordan, David Starr, 1851-1931.; Jordan, Jesse Knight, 1867?-1952.; Lane, Franklin Knight, 1864-1921.; LeConte, John Lawrence, 1825-1883.; MacManus, Seumas, 1869-1960.; McMaster, John Bach, 1852-1932.; Mann, Horace, 1796-1859.; Muir, John, 1838-1914.; Orton, Edward Francis Baxter, 1829-1899.; O'Sullivan, Seumas, 1879-1958.; Peabody, Andrew Preston, 1811-1893.; Shillaber, Benjamin Penhallow, 1814-1890.; Sill, Edward Rowland, 1841-1887.; Steffens, Joseph Lincoln, 1866-1936.; Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968.; Stillman, John Maxson, 1852-1923.; Taft, Alphonso, 1810-1891.; Wilson, Maude J.; Wilson, Woodrow, 1856-1924.; Cuala Press; American literature--20th century.; Women.
Container List
- Letter from John Steinbeck (1902 - ) regarding Phelan award. Miss Anne Hadden's letter of recommednation to Phelan Award Committee. 1935 (Folder 1)
- Richard Henry Dana, Jr. (1815 - 1882) Letter invitation to funeral, 1882, Jan. 7 (Folder 2)
- Anne Hadden letters from W.R. Dudley, W.L. Jepson, David Starr Jordan, MArgaret W. Beck, Mary Austin, Seomas O'Sullivan (James Sullivan Starkey) 1879 - ? H. Sheeley Skeffington, Jessie K. Jordan and Lucie Stern. Includes a mimeographed letter about Miss Hadden's death. (Folder 3)
- Letters to or collected by Irene Hardy (not all names represented in this collection listed.) (Folder 4)
  - Anessoff, P.P. 1889, Apr. 24
  - Barton, Clara 1878, Apr. 15
  - Bradley, C. B. 1913, Mar. 10
  - Callifer, Robert 1868, Aug. 31
  - Coolbirth, Ina 1882, Feb. 1
  - Craig, Austin 1886, June 4
  - Crowley, Wallace 1870, Sept. 29
  - Curtis, George William 1882, Dec. 12
  - Dana, James D. 1882, Dec. 13
  - Derby, S.C. 1880, Dec. 1
  - Formes, E. Karl 1892, Mar. 9
  - Hale, Ellen Day 1870, Jan. 10
  - Hale, Edward Everett 1870, May 6
  - Henry, Joseph 1876, June 21
  - Herferd, Brooke 1876, May 3
  - Holmes, Oliver Wendell 1873, Dec. 7
  - Hamilton, Gail -- pseudonym of Mary Abigail 1913, Mar. 2
  - Lane, Franklin Wright 1876, Dec. 12
  - Le Conte, John Lawrence 1879, Mar. 11
  - Mann, Horace 1887, Mar. 31
  - McMaster, John Back 1859, Mar. 11
  - May, Sam J. 1883, Sept. 27
  - Morris, I.S. 1866, Dec. 6
  - Morrison, R.G. 1876, June 27
  - Muir, John n.d.
  - Orton, Edward Francis Baxter 1868, May 2
  - Peabody, Andrew Preston 1876, Apr. 2
  - Shillaber, Benjamin Penhallow 1871, Dec. 25
  - Sill, Edward Roland 1877, Aug - 1884, Mar. 6
  - Taft, Alphonso 1876, Mar. 6
- Letters to Irene Hardy by Stanford University Faculty. Melville Best Anderson, Ewald Flugel, John M. Stillman, Julia Gilbert. (Folder 5)
- Anne Hadden letters from Seumas MacManus, 1864 - (Folder 6)
  - a) no date
  - b) December 7, 1931
  - c) January 23, 1932
  - d) October, 1934
  - e) October 1, 1934
  - f) October 11, 1934
  - g) November 20, 1934
- Letters to Maude J. Wilson (includes a biographical sketch of Miss Wilson) (Folder 7)
  - L. Adams Beck 1925, Aug. 18
  - Woodrow Wilson 1923, July 2
  - Melville Best Anderson 1921, Nov. 28
  - Lincoln Steffens 1918, Apr. 19
  - Algernon Blackburn 1919, Nov. 12
  - David Starr Jordan 1919, June 6
- Autographs clipped from letters and miscellaneous from the papers of Irene Hardy. (Folder 8)
- Material from the Cuala Press and Yeats family. (Folder 9)